Hair Love is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Matthew A. Cherry.
When dad has to unexpectedly step in for mom to do his daughter Zuri’s hair before a big event, what
seems like a simple task is anything but as these locks have a mind of their own!
Natural Hair Vlogger / Mom (voice), played by Issa Rae.
Hair Love is a 2019 American independent animated
short film
directed by Matthew A.
Cherry, Everett Downing Jr., and Bruce W.
Smith, and written by Cherry.
It follows the story of a man who must do his daughter's hair for the
first time, and features Issa Rae as the voice of the mother.
The film was produced after a 2017 Kickstarter campaign, and was also released as a
children's book in May 2019 with illustrations by Vashti Harrison.
Hair Love received generally positive reviews and won Best
Animated Short Film at the 92nd Academy Awards.
A spin-off TV series titled Young Love was ordered by Max in
July 2020 and premiered on September 21, 2023.
The film explores themes of hairstyle, hair, self love,
father daughter relationship, african american.
The tone is lighthearted.